《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我明早要开始新工作
I start a new job in the morning.
新工作  恭喜
A new job? Congratulations.
我要来哥谭市警局工作了
I'm coming to work at the GCPD.
我是你们的新法医
I'm you're new medical examiner.
我有一些问题要问董事会
I have some questions I need to ask the members of the board.
什么样的问题
What kind of questions?
关于阿卡姆的问题
About Arkham.
看起来那些黑帮的股权
It seems very likely those gangsters were actually
都是韦恩集团提供的
given their shares in Arkham by Wayne Enterprises.
这间夜店能挣大钱
This nightclub makes a lot of money.
所以我要重开这间夜店
That's why I want to reopen it.
你来打理
Under your care.
我可以拥有这间夜店吗
I can have the club?
你现在是我的人了
You're with me now.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
我们在哪
Where are we?
有人觉得是监狱
Some people think it's a prison.
有人觉得是地狱
Some think it's Hell.
他们挖了我的眼睛
They took my eyes.
大家叫他梅斯
People call him Mace.
他是管事的
He's the one in charge?
我叫菲什・穆尼
My name is Fish Mooney.
我现在是老大了
I'm in charge now.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
就是这首歌
Here's that song...
当你微笑时*
*When you're smiling...
*When you're smiling
整个世界*
*The whole world
都随之微笑*
*Smiles with you
当你笑的时候*
*When you're laughing...
她在干吗
What's she doing?
当你笑的时候*
*When you're laughing
太阳*
*The sun
散发出光芒*
*Comes shining through
但当你哭的时候*
*But when you're crying
你会带来阴雨*
*You bring on that rain
别再叹息*
*So stop your sighing
重新快乐起来吧*
*Be happy again
继续微笑*
*Keep on smiling
因为当你微笑时*
*'Cause when you're smiling
整个世界都会跟着你微笑*
*That whole world smiles with you...
翻译：DustD   Reginamoon   charcie   木浅薰   Silence
翻译：草草   灰灰是菇凉             特效：宝宝
时间轴：Kallen   艹明   最可爱的小胖子
后期：饿得慌          校对&总监：草草
吉姆
Jim?
吉姆在哪
Where's Jim?
他上周就来还了钥匙
He dropped off his keys, like, last week.
那随他去了  是不是
So screw him anyway, right?
你们是谁
So who are you guys?
谢谢
Thanks.
女士们先生们  飞人格雷森一家
Ladies and gentlemen, The Flying Graysons!
向大家表示感谢吧
Show them your appreciation!
飞人格雷森一家感谢您
Thank you from the Flying Graysons!
谢谢您  谢谢您
Thank you! Thank you!
他在干吗
What's he doing?
借过
Coming through!
快回去  你在干吗...
Get back in there! What do you...?
冷静点  冷静  停手
Calm down, now. Calm down! Stop that!
别这样
Come on!
停手  冷静点
Stop it! Calm down!
-女士们  别这样  -我恨你
- Ladies, come on! - I hate you!
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
所有人都别动
Everybody freeze!
整个世界*
*The whole world
随着你微笑*
*Smiles with you.
下去吧  你这老婆子
Get off, you old bag.
你...
You...
哥谭
第一季  第十六集
你为什么要攻击格雷森先生
Why did you attack Mr. Grayson?
不为什么
No reason.
我不喜欢他
I don't like him.
我不知道他为什么要这样
I have no idea why he did it.
我怎么知道
Beats me.
你们马戏团的都动真格的啊
Wow, you circus people don't mess around, do you?
我发誓  约翰・格雷森
I swear, John Grayson,
如果你再这样看着我
if you give me that look one more time,
我就一巴掌扇上去
I will slap you silly.
你想得美
You wish.
别以为我不敢
Don't think I can't.
好了  孩子们
Whoa, kids.
你们这是有什么矛盾啊
What's the big problem, anyhow?
格雷森一家都是自负的混蛋  就这问题
The Graysons are a bunch of arrogant buttheads is the problem.
劳埃德一家都是不负责任的酒鬼
The Lloyds are feckless drunkards,
这才是问题
is more like it.
那么是家族世仇了
So it's a family feud.
格雷森一家和劳埃德一家有过节
Graysons don't get along with Lloyds.
已经有很多年了
Been that way for years.
都已经成为传统了
It's sort of a tradition.
你们每晚都这样打一架吗
You guys fight like this every night?
不是
No.
那只是她蠢货叔叔在犯蠢
That was just her idiot uncle doing his thing.
你明明知道肯定是因为莱拉
You know damn well it must be Lila's fault.
-玛莉  -干吗
- Mary... - What?
抱歉约会被毁了
Sorry the date went south.
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
最棒的一次约会
Best date ever.
可不是谁都能看到马戏团斗殴
Who gets to see a circus brawl?
也是
True.
他们都不肯开口
None of them will talk, of course.
所以我不知道他们为什么打架
So I've no idea what those two were fighting over.
我觉得他们是情敌
I think they're rival lovers.
他们家族很早之前就开始互相敌视了
Their families have been fighting since way back,
但是这次打架
but this particular fight
显然是为了一个名叫莱拉的女人
was apparently over a woman named Lila.
她是穿插表演的蛇舞演员
She's a Snake Dancer in the sideshow.
是啊  多酷啊  一位蛇舞演员
I know. How cool is that? A snake dancer.
我是说  你干的真棒
No, I mean, wow, you're really good.
-人们愿意对医生开口  -看来是的
- People talk to doctors. - I guess so.
我得去找到这个莱拉
I should find this woman Lila,
确保她没事
make sure she's okay.
可能会需要点时间
Might take little awhile.
我让巡警载你回家好了
I'll have a patrolman drive you home.
我可以和你一起去啊
I could come with you.
小莱  这是警方事务
Lee, this is police business.
拜托了  吉姆
Come on, Jim.
我好想见见莱拉
I'm dying to meet Lila.
带着医护人员
Well, bringing along medical personnel
倒也算是合理的预防措施吧
is a justifiable precaution, I guess.
这就是了
There you go.
先生...莱拉在哪
Sir... where's Lila?
莱拉
Lila?
那个蛇舞演员
The Snake Dancer.
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
我们要和莱拉谈谈
We need to speak with Lila.
她不在这里
She's not here.
怎么了  发生什么了
Why? What's happened?
她在哪里
Where is she?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
她早就应该回家了
She was supposed to be home ages ago.
你是她亲戚吗
You a relative?
我是她儿子  杰罗姆
Uh, I'm her son-- Jerome.
杰罗姆  你最后一次见到她是什么时候
Jerome, when did you last see her?
今早
This morning.
我出发去图书馆时她还在这里
She was here when I left for the library.
放松  杰罗姆  这位先生来这里
Relax, Jerome, this gentleman is just here
只是因为欧文和阿尔起了点争执
because Owen and Al had a disagreement.
你妈妈没事的  肯定又是去寻欢了
Your mother's fine, gone on a spree, no doubt.
-你知道她的  -寻欢
- You know how she is. - A spree?
没戴帽子  没穿大衣  钱包也没带吗
Without her hat, her coat or her purse?
看看希巴
And look at Sheba.
她心神不宁的
She's distraught.
她知道出事了
She knows something's wrong.
那条蛇看起来是有点烦躁啊
The snake does seem to be agitated.
警官...
Sir...
她就是那种交际女
she's what you call a party girl.
早上就会回来了  包里装着小内裤
Back in the morning with her knickers in a handbag,
毫无疑问
sure as eggs.
但她没带包啊  不是吗
But she didn't take her handbag, did she?
蛇移动速度能有多快
How fast does an animal like that move?
人类快走的速度
Oh, fast walking pace.
它们主要是靠偷袭取胜
They rely on surprise, mainly.
放她出来
Let her out.
什么
I'm sorry?
放她出来
Let her out.
天呐
Oh, my God.
你知道
You knew.
你知道她在这里
You knew she was here.
不知道
No.
看着我
Look at me.
我们找到她时她就那样了
She was like that when we found her.
咱们打开天窗说亮话吧
Let's talk straight.
上面那些人
Those people out there
利用我们作为移植手术的供体
are using us as transplant donors.
我们只是零部件
We are simply spare parts.
除非...
Unless...
除非我们有所行动
unless we do something about it.
怎么行动
How?
我有个计划
I have a plan.
但是你们必须完全照我说的做
But you must do exactly what I say.
你们听我的  我保证
You do as I say, and I promise you,
我能把我们中一部分人  活着弄出去
I will get some of us out of here alive.
没错
That's right.
是的  你们没听错
No, you heard me correctly.
我说的是  我们中...一部分人
I said, some... of us.
因为事实就是一部分人会死掉
Because the truth of the matter is some will die.
但是我们会有尊严地死去
But we will die with dignity.
我们会死得其所
We will die for a reason,
我们会和家人死在一起
and we will die next to family,
而我要告诉你们  我们是一家人
and I tell you what-- we are family.
我们只有彼此
We're all we got.
那就是家人
That's family!
我们的选择很简单
We have one simple choice:
我们跪着孤单死在这里
we die here alone on our knees
或是我们站起来和家人一起战斗
or we stand up and we fight with our family!
几个流浪汉在这里发现了她
A couple of riggers found her right here.
我们决定把她藏在卡车上
We decided to hide her on the truck.
我们本打算一上路
We were going to give her a proper burial
就给她办个体面的葬礼
as soon as we got back on the road.
你还真是好心
Decent of you.
"我们"是指谁  还有谁知道
Who's "we"? Who else knew?
只有我和家长
Just me and the head of the families.
假如是外人杀了她  还能怎么办
If an outsider killed her, what can you do?
只能说是天意了
An act of God.
假如是我们的人做的
If it was one of us,
我们总会查明的
we always find out.
我们会确保此人得到惩罚
And we make sure they're punished.
怎么惩罚
How?
我们自有办法
We have our ways.
我们也有
And we have ours.
把他铐起来
Hook him up.
早上好啊  搭档
Morning, partner.
我需要你帮忙
Gonna need a little help here.
真不是开玩笑
No kidding.
你开玩笑吧
I mean, you're kidding, right?
这不会是恶作剧吧
This isn't an elaborate prank or...?
说说你母亲  杰罗姆
Tell me about your mother, Jerome.
她是我母亲
She's my mother.
还能说什么  我爱她
What can I say? I love her.
她很完美
She's perfect.
不算个好厨子
Not a very good cook.
除此以外都好
Except for that...
她有敌人吗
Did she have any enemies?
跟谁结过仇
Someone with a grudge?
没有
No.
男友呢
Boyfriends?
没有
No.
没有吗
No?
她有过很多情人
She had lovers.
其实就是炮友  都不是男友
They're sex partners really, but not boyfriends.
她不想给人承诺
She didn't want the commitment.
阿方斯・格雷森是吗
Alphonse Grayson?
是的  他是其中之一
Yes, he was one of them.
欧文・劳埃德呢
Owen Lloyd?
也是
Yes.
还有别人吗
Any others?
我说得上名字的就这两个
Not that I could put a name to.
你怎么看你母亲的感情生活
How do you feel about your mother's love life?
我无所谓
I feel fine about it.
如果不是因为她有感情生活
If not for my mother's love life,
我也不会出生了  对不对
I wouldn't be here, would I?
性是健康的人类活动
Sex is a healthy human activity.
没错  是的
Yes, it is.
你还有其他家人吗
Do you have any other family?
马戏团就是我的家
The circus is my family.
我再问一遍  你为什么要打格雷森先生
One more time. Why did you assault Mr. Grayson?
你知道为什么
You know why.
-说说吧  -他杀了莱拉
- Tell me. - He killed Lila.
他为什么要杀她
Why would he do that?
因为她要选我而放弃他
She was gonna choose me over him,
而他是个自大的混蛋
and he's an arrogant son of a bitch.
不愿让劳埃德家的人那样侮辱格雷森家的人
Not gonna let a Lloyd humiliate a Grayson that way.
你们两家人为什么合不来
How come your families don't get along?
他曾祖父
His great-grandfather
冤枉我母亲的叔叔巴瑞偷马
falsely accused my mother's uncle Barry of stealing a horse.
这什么时候的事
When was this?
大战之前
Before the Great War.
-第一次世界大战  -是
- World War One. - Yeah.
你们两家
For three generations,
三代敌视就因为一匹被偷的马
your families have been feuding over a stolen horse?
是的  劳埃德一家人仍是一群渣滓
Yes. And the Lloyds are still trash.
基因不会变
Blood is blood.
那匹马一定很贵重
Must be a hell of a horse.
劳埃德先生为什么要打你
Why did Mr. Lloyd assault you?
因为他杀了莱拉  怕我会因此杀了他
He killed Lila, and fears I'm gonna kill him for it.
他的说法正相反
He says the opposite.
他说是你杀了她
He says you killed her.
是啊  他当然会这么说了
Yes, I suppose he would have to say that, wouldn't he?
不是欧文叔叔
It wasn't Uncle Owen.
他绝不会做这么可怕的事
He could never do such a terrible thing.
我靠  玛莉
Holy crap, Mary!
你怎么这么不长眼睛
How can you be so blind?
你闭嘴
Quiet, you.
就是  你闭嘴
Yeah, quiet, you.
你才不长眼睛呢
You're the blind one.
我哥哥是正人君子
My brother is a man of honor.
你叔叔是暴力酒鬼
Your uncle is a violent drunk.
-算算吧  小女孩  -我叔叔是位艺人
- Do the math, little girl. - My uncle is an artist.
你哥哥是个自大的肌肉男
Your brother is a conceited muscle-head,
你们这群飞人傻帽都一个样
like the rest of you flying douche bags.
真不敢相信我还以为自己爱你
I can't believe I ever thought I loved you.
够了
Enough.
他们来了
They're coming.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
准备好了
Yes!
准备好了吗
I said, are you ready?!
准备好了
Yes!
57A号犯人  举起手来
Inmate 57A, raise your hand.
57A
57A...
举起手来
Raise your hand.
向前一步
Step forward.
请等等  先生
One moment, please, sir.
咱们得谈谈
We need to talk.
往后退  犯人
Back up, inmate.
你违规了
You're in violation.
57A
57A,
向前一步
step forward!
打断一下  谢谢
Excuse me one moment, please.
现在这里我说了算
I'm the new "Shot caller" here.
我叫菲什・穆尼
My name is Fish Mooney,
无意冒犯  不过为了你我
and with all due respect, for you and I
今后能营造良好的工作关系
to have a good working relationship,
有些规矩恐怕得改改
there's some things that need to change.
是吗
Is that right?
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫什么名字你管不着
None of your damn business what my name is.
好吧
Right. Okay, well...
我知道你现在公务在身
I know you have a job to do.
而我也很乐意把57A交给你
And I am more than willing to give you 57A,
不过我要你拿60箱饮用水
in exchange for 60 crates of water,
30条毛毯  50磅新鲜水果
30 blankets, 50 pounds of fresh fruit,
还有几本杂志来换
and a few magazines.
我要是拒绝呢
What if I refuse?
你会怎么办
What will you do?
我还是一样乐意把57A交给你
Well, I'd be willing to give you 57A,
只是要交死的了
just not alive.
我们要活的
We need them alive.
我知道啊
Exactly.
我数到三之前
I'm gonna count to three.
你赶紧闪人
You'll disappear
否则我让你吃不了兜着走
or get a severe beating.
我想你这算是拒绝了吧
I'm gonna take that as a no.
一
One...
二
two...
这是简单的生意经
It's simple economics.
我们的命是有价值的
Our lives are worth something.
我要60箱饮用水  30条毛毯
60 crates of water, 30 blankets...
你
You...
你跟我走
you're coming with me.
主管一定会生你气的
The Manager is gonna be very unhappy with you.
我想这位主管
I would think this Manager
对你也不会很满意吧
wouldn't be too happy with you either.
所以如果他想跟我谈
So if he wants to talk to me,
我就在这儿等他
I'll be right here.
主管不会下来这里
Manager doesn't come down here.
看来我们是陷入僵局了
Well, looks like we have a standoff.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
我很好说话的
I can be flexible.
我可以去见这位主管
So I'll go talk to this Manager,
但我离开期间  你得作为贵宾
but while I'm gone, you're going to stay right here,
留在这里
as our guest.
怎么样
How's that sound?
我们还会回来的
We'll be back.
耶
Yeah!
等等  往回倒
Wait, back up a little.
你放出了蛇吗
So you set the snake loose?
-是的  长官  -为了追踪尸体
- Yes, ma'am. - To track down the body?
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
蛇嗅觉十分敏锐
Snakes have an excellent sense of smell.
嗯  长知识了
Well, now I know.
而你的头号嫌疑人是个小丑和一个杂技演员
And your prime suspects are a clown and an acrobat?
没错
Yeah.
他很厉害吧
Ain't this one a doozy?
被害人  莱拉・瓦勒斯卡
Your victim, Lila Valeska,
是被一把大刀或短柄斧砍伤致死
was killed by a large knife or hatchet.
头部和躯干多处受创
Multiple blows to the head and upper torso.
死亡时间大概是昨天下午3点
Around 3:00 yesterday afternoon.
2点30到4点15  格雷森和劳埃德
From 2:30 to 4:15, both Grayson and Lloyd
都在马戏团参加日场表演
were in the ring for the matinee.
死亡时间的精确度是多少
Well, how precise is that time of death?
误差在45分钟左右吧
Give or take 45 minutes.
那么还是有做案可能  但时间窗很短
Still possible then, but cutting it close.
拘留嫌疑人  施以压力
Hold and press your guys,
但继续寻找其他嫌疑人
but keep looking.
好  老大  鉴证组正在检查案发现场
Yeah, boss. Forensics is working the crime scene now.
我们去检查她的电话记录
We're going through her phone records.
好了
All right!
你们剩下的人可以回家了
We're gonna send the rest of you home now,
但是调查还在继续
but the investigation is ongoing.
谁也不许出城
Nobody leaves town.
而且给我听好
And listen up.
不许再打架了
No more fighting!
看看你们朋友的下场
Look where your friends are.
这世仇对你们有什么好处
What good is this feud doing you?
我喜欢你强硬的样子
I like it when you act all tough.
"谁也不许出城"
"Nobody leave town."
你说起来更好听
Sounds better when you say it.
我觉得我们该继续中断的约会
I feel like we should finish up our date.
今晚你想来我家吗
Do you want to come over tonight?
我可以给你做晚餐
I can cook you dinner.
好啊  听起来不错
Sure. That sounds good.
好
Good.
-好好休息  -我尽力  晚上见
- Get some rest. - I will try. See you later.
我得问
I have to ask.
如果要你猜  你认为是谁杀了莱拉
If you were to guess, who do you think killed Lila?
我尽量不瞎猜
I try not to guess.
我审问疑犯  等待鉴证报告
I work the suspects and I wait on forensics.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你是詹姆斯・戈登警探吗
Am I speaking to Detective James Gordon?
是的
Yes.
那这位肯定是汤普金斯医生  验尸官
Then this must be Dr. Thompkins, the medical examiner.
抱歉  你怎么知道我们是谁
I'm sorry, how did you know who we were?
我叫保罗・西瑟罗
My name is Paul Cicero.
我是穿插表演的灵媒
I'm a psychic with the sideshow.
莱拉・瓦勒斯卡是我的老朋友
Lila Valeska was an old friend of mine.
灵媒  知道了
A psychic. I see.
有什么能帮你的  西瑟罗先生
How could I help you, Mr. Cicero?
我觉得你认为欧文和阿方斯均是无罪的
I sense that you don't think Owen or Alphonse are guilty.
你肯定是个灵媒
You must be psychic.
所以  也许你想听听莱拉
In which case, perhaps you'd like to hear the message
从亡灵世界给我发来的讯息
Lila sent me from the other side.
谢谢你  西瑟罗先生
Thanks, Mr. Cicero,
我们还没开始调查亡灵世界呢
we're not quite looking at the other side just yet.
随便你  我只不过是个信差
As you wish. I'm merely a messenger.
是什么讯息
What's the message?
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
莱拉告诉我说  魔鬼的仆人
Lila told me that the servant of the Devil
躺在铁姐妹的花园里
lies in the garden of the Iron Sisters.
铁姐妹
The Iron Sisters?
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
不知道
I don't know.
我们这就去调查
We'll get right on it.
我认为讽刺不是你的专长  詹姆斯
I don't think sarcasm is your métier, James.
随你怎么利用这条讯息吧
Make of the message what you will.
祝你们俩安好
Good day to you both.
你的偏见好大啊
Well, that wasn't very open-minded of you.
拜托  小莱  他就是个骗子
Oh, come on, Lee. He's a fraud.
他会直接去找媒体
He's gonna go straight to the press
说自己是这起案子的顾问
and say he's consulting on the case.
他是在藉机宣传
He's looking for publicity.
也许吧
Maybe.
如果人死后  还会发来讯息
If you were gonna send a message from beyond the grave,
那首先要说的
don't you think priority number one
不该是凶手的姓名  而不是谜语吗
would be the killer's name and not a riddle?
谁知道这种事是怎么回事
Who knows how it works?
好吧  我不想和你争论
All right. I'm not gonna argue with you.
很好
Good.
那回头见了
Later, then.
回头见
Later.
他们打电话来确认
They called to confirm
你明天和韦恩集团董事会的会议
your meeting with the board of Wayne Enterprises tomorrow.
好极了
Excellent.
我还担心他们会再次延期
I was afraid they'd postpone again.
我再说一次
Well, I'll say it one more time.
我认为
I think that, uh,
这个主意很不好  布鲁斯少爷
it's an incredibly bad idea, Master Bruce.
我觉得太草率  太仓促
I think it's reckless, I think it's premature,
而且坦白地说  我认为这样做非常危险
and, quite frankly, I think it's bloody dangerous.
我们已经讨论过很多次了  阿尔弗雷德
And we've already been over this 100 times, Alfred.
我主意已定
My mind is made up.
能把那份文件递给我吗
Can you pass me that file over there?
文件
The file...
好吧
well...
该说的我都说了
I've said my piece.
如果我们俩被人发现死在沟里  别怪我
If we're both found dead in a ditch, don't blame me.
不行
Nah.
不行吗
No?
吉姆喜欢我穿这个颜色的衣服
Jim loves me in this color.
太明显了
It's too obvious.
你要穿得不那么刻意
You gotta dress like you're not trying,
像是你要去和别的男人见面那样
like you're on your way to go meet some other guy.
出去远航
To go... sailing,
或别的什么事
or whatever.
不是吧  出航吗
Really? Sailing?
好吧
Okay.
天呐
Oh, my God.
你喜欢吗
You like?
天呐  太好吃了
Oh, my God.
天呐
Oh, my God!
出什么事了
What's wrong?
是好事
No, it's good.
我用了我姐姐的菜谱
It's my sister's recipe;
她做饭手艺极佳
she's a really, brilliant cook.
我正想着我姐
I was thinking of my sister,
然后就突然想到
and it came to me:
我想我知道那个盲眼人的讯息指什么了
I think I know what the blind man's message means.
魔鬼的仆人
The servant of the devil
躺在铁姐妹的花园里
lies in the garden of the Iron Sisters?
是阿卡姆大桥
It's Arkham Bridge.
铁姐妹  就是阿卡姆大桥
The Iron Sisters. Arkham Bridge.
桥两边的塔楼  叫玛丽和贝蒂
The towers. They're called, uh, Mary and Betty?
我还记得小时候
I remember, as a kid,
我们就这么叫  可...
we used to call them that, but...
没错  那里还有个公园  就在塔楼下
Right. And there's a park, um, under the towers
靠近哥谭这边
on the Gotham side.
花园  都合上了
A garden? It all fits.
小莱
Lee...
但这是不可能的
it fits an impossible story.
他没跟莱拉・瓦勒斯卡交谈过
He didn't speak with Lila Valeska,
-她已经死了  -这只是你的看法
- she's dead. - So you say!
得了  你是个医生  一个科学家
Come on, you're a doctor. A scientist.
这世上有很多东西
There are plenty of things in this world
是无法用理性科学来解释的
that can't be explained by rational science.
是啊  比如那些喜欢跳土风舞的人
Yeah, people who enjoy folk dancing, for instance.
这不代表鬼是存在的
Doesn't mean ghosts exist.
你的自信好盛气凌人啊
You're very arrogant in your certainty.
万一这是凶案的线索呢
What if this is a clue to a murder?
想想那个可怜的女人
The poor woman!
好吧  我会亲自去查看
Fine. I'll go myself.
-谢谢  -没事
- Thank you. - Sure.
-我跟你一起去  -好
- I'll come with you. - Okay.
我们一起去  明天一早就去
We'll go together. First thing in the morning.
一早
Morning?
现在
Now?
你想现在去吗
You want to go now?
离这里只有半英里
It's only a half a mile away.
已经天黑了
It's dark.
我有手电筒
I have a flashlight.
我们到底要找什么  你知道吗
So what are we looking for, exactly, do you think?
我明白  我明白
I know, I know.
也许我们只是在白费功夫
This is probably a complete waste of time.
-谢谢你愿意陪我出来  -不用谢
- Thank you for doing this. - No problem.
不过  不要习以为常了  好吗
But, uh, let's not make a habit out of it, okay?
这不是女士该来的地方
This is no place for a lady.
呵呵
Ha!
"呵呵"什么
What do you mean, "Ha"?
你好虚伪
You're a hypocrite.
你说你想要一个坚强的女人
You say you want a strong woman
与你分享你选择的疯狂人生
to share this crazy life you've chosen,
可在紧要关头
but when push comes to shove,
你却要我待在家里烤饼干
you want me to stay home and bake cookies.
不非得是饼干
Not cookies, necessarily.
烤派也行  什么派都行
Pie. Any kind of pie.
呵呵
Ha, ha!
如果有人从桥上的车里往下扔了什么东西
So if someone were to throw something from a car on the bridge,
就会落在这里
this is where it would land.
你想得没错
Yeah, I guess you're right.
小莱
Lee...
THFC
THFC.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
地狱火俱乐部
The Hellfire Club.
是一个撒旦崇拜邪教
It's a Satanist cult.
过去犯下过很多祭祀性凶杀案
Committed a string of ritual murders.
可是他们已经沉寂十余年了
But they haven't been active for a decade or more.
看来他们回来了
I guess they're back.
不
No.
我不这么认为
No, I don't think so.
警司  给我找几个巡警
Hey, Sarge, I'm gonna need a couple of mobile units
去帮我带几个人回局里
to pick some people up.
听着  务必谨慎对待
But listen... they need careful handling.
长官  他们在3号室和4号室
Sir, they're in three and four.
谢了  齐克  他们都不知道
Thanks, Zeke. Neither of them knows
对方也在这里  对吧
the other one's here, right?
对  如你吩咐的
Right, like you said.
干得好
Ah, good work.
记住  也许你的想法
Just bear in mind that you could be wrong
-都是错的  -我会记住的
- about all of this. - I will bear it in mind.
我会的  但是我没错
I will, but I'm not wrong.
回家去吧  女士
So go on home now, lady.
当时我们正在共度美好的夜晚
We were having a perfectly lovely evening.
想出门寻找
I am not the one who wanted
撒旦崇拜短柄斧的人可不是我
to go out searching for Satanist hatchets.
你明知道我想做什么
You... know what I wanted to do.
你说得对
You're right.
什么  你说什么
Uh-huh. I'm sorry, what?
我经常热心过度
I tend to get overly enthusiastic about things.
这是我的问题
It's an issue for me.
我妈常说...
My mom always said...
谁管我妈说了什么呢
Oh, who gives a crap what my mom said, right?
晚上愉快  吉姆
Have a good night, Jim.
回头把结果告诉我
Let me know how it all turns out.
再见  小莱
Good night, Lee.
等等
Wait!
你之前的话
What you said earlier,
说我虚伪  还有关于分享生活
about hypocrisy, sharing lives...
你说得对  我们走吧
You're right. Let's go.
我什么
I'm what?
说对了
Right.
晚上好  西瑟罗先生
Good evening, Mr. Cicero.
抱歉这么晚叫您来
Sorry to bring you down here so late.
晚上好  戈登警探
Good evening, Detective Gordon;
还有汤普金斯医生
Dr. Thompkins.
你怎么...
How did you...
他闻到你香水了
He smells your perfume.
我们破解了莱拉给你捎的话
We solved the message Lila sent you.
我们按线索去了阿卡姆大桥公园
Took us to Arkham Bridge Park.
在那里发现了一把短柄斧
We found a hatchet there
上面刻了撒旦标记
with Satanist symbols scratched into it.
天呐
Dear lord.
你知道那把斧子意味着什么吗  西瑟罗先生
You know what that hatchet means, Mr. Cicero?
说说吧
Tell me.
意味着你是谋杀从犯
It means you're an accessory to murder.
这么夸张
Such drama.
我不过是捎了个信
I merely passed along a message.
死人捎来的信
A message from the dead.
根本没那回事
Didn't happen.
所以  那个讯息是你编的
Which means you invented the message...
所以  你找人去留下把斧子让我们找到
which means you had someone plant the hatchet for us to find.
你想让我们以为
You wanted us to think
是撒旦崇拜者杀害了莱拉
Satanist were responsible for Lila's death.
你在保护一个人
You're protecting somebody.
莱拉给我托话了
Lila spoke to me.
就是这样
That's all.
知道吗
You know,
短柄斧是个拙劣的计谋
a hatchet is a clumsy ploy.
你能这么做也是别无选择
You wouldn't try it unless you were desperate.
所以你一定是在保护一个亲近的人
Which suggests you're protecting someone close.
你爱的人
Someone you love.
这个幻想
This fantasia
不过是你狭隘的头脑编出来的
was conjured in your blinkered mind.
如果你能有我的视界
If you could only see what I see...
你好啊  杰罗姆
Hi, Jerome.
请坐
Please. Take a seat.
你认识西瑟罗先生的  是剧团的人
You know Mr. Cicero, from the show.
是  警官
Yes, sir.
你好  西瑟罗先生
Hello, Mr. Cicero.
晚上好  杰罗姆
Good evening, Jerome.
知道为什么叫你来吗
Do you know why you're here?
你查明是谁杀了我母亲吗
Did you find out who killed my mother?
是你杀了你母亲  杰罗姆
You killed your mother, Jerome.
我
Me?
你在山上杀了她
You killed her up on that hill
西瑟罗先生让你去他拖车上收拾干净
and Mr. Cicero let you clean up in his trailer.
他叫你在短柄斧上留下撒旦标记
He told you to scratch the Satanist stuff on the hatchet
然后扔下桥
and throw it off the bridge.
警官  这太荒谬了
Sir, that's... absurd and...
而且很过分
and offensive.
事实就是如此
But it's the truth.
但我不知道此人为什么如此冒险帮你
What I don't know is why this man risked so much to help you.
我认为他是你父亲
I think he's your father.
你在胡说
You don't know what you're talking about.
我父亲是位船长
My father was a sea captain.
我说错了吗  西瑟罗先生
Am I wrong, Mr. Cicero?
错了
Yes.
他是个船长
He was a sea captain.
他叫斯文・卡尔森  他死在了海上
His name was Sven Karlsen. He died at sea.
那艘船叫什么
What was the name of his ship?
他在很多船上干过活儿
He worked on a lot of different ships.
跟他一起沉没的那艘呢
The one he went down in.
她没说过
She never said.
我们可以做血检证实一下
We can do a blood test to prove I'm right.
一小时内就能拿到准确结果
It takes only half an hour to get a foolproof result.
是不是  汤普金斯医生
Isn't that right, Dr. Thompkins?
是的
Yes.
别去挨那一针了
Save yourself a needle.
我的确讨厌扎针
I do hate needles.
对不起  杰罗姆
I'm sorry, Jerome.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
他说得对
He's right.
我是你父亲
I am your father.
不  你不是  你为什么这么说
No, you're not. Why would you say that?
你一定也有所怀疑
You must have suspected the truth.
你不是我父亲  我母亲绝不会
You're not my father. My mother would never...
你母亲是个冷酷的女人
Your mother was a cruel woman;
她对我经常很刻薄
she was often unkind to me,
但她曾爱过我
but she did once love me,
以她的方式
in her way.
她也很爱你
And she loved you very much.
所以她给你编造了一个更好的父亲
That's why she gave you a better father.
我母亲
My mother
是个冷血的婊子
was a cold-hearted whore
她从未爱过任何人
who never loved anyone.
她才不会
And she'd never touch
碰你这样可悲的老变态呢
a pathetic old creep like you.
这些年来
All these years,
你以为我是好心
do you think I was kind to you
才对你那么好的吗
because I'm such a good man?
如果我不是你父亲
If I wasn't your father,
怎么会得知你做了那种事  还那么帮你
would I help you as I have, after what you did?
我父亲
My father...
真没想到
I'll be damned.
真是好笑啊
Oh, that's very funny.
看来那婊子到底震惊了我一把
Looks like the bitch got me with a zinger in the end.
你为什么杀你母亲  杰罗姆
Why did you kill your mother, Jerome?
你也知道母亲都什么德行
Oh, you know how mothers are.
她就是一直逼我
She just kept pushing.
我心想  好啊  老妈
And I'm like, fine, Mom.
当你的婊子去吧
Be a whore.
当个酒鬼婊子吧
Be a drunken whore, even.
但别当个
But don't be
唠唠叨叨的酒鬼婊子
a nagging drunken whore.
明白吗
You know?
别跑来吼我
Don't come yell at me
叫我洗盘子
to do the dishes
你还一直在隔壁屋里上小丑呢
if you've been banging a clown in the next room!
懂吗
You know?
累了吧
Long night, huh?
居然闹得这么难看
Guess it got kind of ugly.
是啊
Yes, it did.
你没事吧
You okay?
我没事
I'm good.
真的
Truly.
虽然很不堪  但也很刺激
It was ugly, but it was also kind of thrilling.
刺激
Thrilling?
刺激  吓人
Thrilling and scary.
就像往一个很深很黑的隧道里看
Like-like looking down a deep, dark tunnel.
谢谢你让我参与
Thanks for letting me be there.
你真是个不寻常的女人
You are an unusual woman.
你就是认识的女人太少罢了
You just don't know many women.
我们能回家了吗
Can we go home now?
你好啊  企鹅
Hello, Penguin.
维克多
Victor.
你能来真好
How nice.
法尔科内阁下觉得你没弄好
Don Falcone thinks you're messing up.
你不会经营夜店
You don't know how to run a club.
你的营业额
Your numbers...
很糟糕
stink.
恕我直言
With all due respect...
我不是来跟你废话的
I didn't come here to talk.
有点礼貌死不了人
Good manners cost nothing, you know?
放松
Relax.
他不会伤人
He's harmless.
打招呼  布奇
Say hi, Butch.
法尔科内不想丢掉他
Falcone didn't want to throw him away,
所以我在地下室里调教了他几周
so I worked on him in my basement for a couple of weeks.
他已经焕然一新了
He's a whole new man.
是吧  布奇
Right, Butch?
是  萨斯先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Zsasz.
布奇十分了解夜店
Butch knows the club scene up and down.
他会帮你的
He'll help you out.
但他...
But he's...
他是布奇・吉尔兹
He's Butch Gilzean.
他忠于菲什・穆尼
He's loyal to Fish Mooney.
他会...
And he'll do...
对你言听计从
exactly what you say.
真的
Really?
Really.
布奇
Hey, Butch,
给我跳支舞
dance for me.
我干得不错吧
I do good work.
各位早上好
Good morning, everyone.
早上好  布鲁斯
Good morning, Bruce.
欢迎来到韦恩集团
Welcome to Wayne Enterprises.
见到你很高兴
So happy to see you.
谢谢你们来见我
Thank you for meeting with me.
我有些关于韦恩集团生意上的问题
I have some questions regarding Wayne Enterprises business affairs.
当然
Of course.
这毕竟是你的公司
It's your company, after all.
问吧  年轻人
Fire away, young man.
我主要有两大疑问
I have two main areas of concern.
阿卡姆项目与黑帮的关联
Underworld involvement in the Arkham Project.
以及下属公司韦赞制药的化学武器制造
And chemical weapons manufacture at our Wellzyn affiliate.
太棒了
That's great.
恭喜二位
Congratulations.
我们想谢谢你
We wanted to thank you.
如果不是你破了莱拉的案子
If you hadn't figure out who killed Lila
还劝我们明白事理
and talked to sense to us the way you did,
我们两家绝不会和解
our families never would have reconciled,
我们也不能在一起了
and we could've never gotten together.
只是尽职而已
Just doing my job.
如果我们生了儿子  就叫他戈登
Hey, if we have a son, we'll name him Gordon.
这个...
Well...
再议吧
we'll discuss that,
但我们真的很感激
but we're certainly very grateful.
不客气
Sure.
怎么这么开心
Why so happy?
群众满意嘛
Happy customers.
才不是为这个
That's not it.
是别的
It's something else.
你昨晚啪啪了吧
You got laid, didn't you?
你厉害
That's impressive.
你在没有剃须刀的地方过夜了
You slept somewhere without razors
还一身女人香皂味儿
and you smell like ladies' soap.
简单
Easy catch.
我只能认为
I can only conclude
韦恩集团内部高层人物或团体
that high-level individuals or groups within Wayne Enterprises
与人勾结  参与了腐败  受贿  敲诈
have colluded in corruption, bribery, racketeering,
和不道德的医疗研究
and unethical medical research.
多谢你发表意见  布鲁斯
Thank you for that input, Bruce.
如果这些令人震惊的传闻或谣言
I'm so sorry if you've been alarmed or upset
令你担忧或难过了
by these shocking stories and rumors
那我很抱歉
you've been exposed to.
这并非仅仅是谣言
These are much more than rumors.
我们会全面彻底地调查的
We'll look into them thoroughly and carefully, of course.
但是  布鲁斯  老实说
Bruce, let's be fair.
你没给出任何实质性的证据
You've told us nothing with any substantive proof behind it.
我还有所保留
I haven't told you all I know.
是吗
No?
还有什么
What else is there?
我希望你真能仔细进行调查
I hope you do look closely into these issues.
因为下次股东大会上  我会提起此事
Because I'll be raising them at the next shareholders' meeting
并考虑采取法律行动
with a view to possible legal action.
天啊
Dear me.
法律行动
Legal action?
你这么年轻  不适合这么深的浑水吧
These are all very deep waters for such a young man.
我的年龄与此无关
My youth is not relevant.
但如果我成年了
Except that if I were a man,
我就会是董事会的主席
I would be chairing this board.
而我一定会保证韦恩集团不干见不得人的勾当
And I would be sure that Wayne Enterprises was run honestly.
谢谢各位前来
Thank you for your time.
主管同意了
The manager says you have a deal.
你上去见他
You go up and see him,
我留下
I stay here.
你叫什么
What's your name?
施密特
Schmidt.
名字
Your first name.
托马斯
Thomas.
欢迎
Welcome.
你不如
Why don't you
卸下沉甸甸的装备
take off that heavy gear
放松一下吧
and relax?
我的家人会好好招待你
My family's gonna show you a good time.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com